FLORIAN BÜHLER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

✓ florian-buehler@outlook.com

in linkedin.com/in/florian-bühler

github.com/florianbuehler

florianbuehler.github.io

KEY SKILLS

FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT

- JavaScript / ES6
- TypeScript
- React.js
- HTML5
- CSS3 / Sass
- Gatsby
- Bootstrap

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT

- C#
- ASP.NET Core
- Node.js
- REST APIs
- Docker
- Postgres

GENERAL

- Docker
- Scrum
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- CI/CD Pipelines
- Domain-Driven Design
- Test-Driven Design

PROFILE

I am a 29-year-old passionate full stack web developer with a strong handson mentality and over 4 years of experience in building web applications from front to back in agile teams. I love to create software to improve real world problems and I strongly believe that anything can be built if it is tackled by a passionate and creative team.

I would describe myself as a person with a strong analytical problem-solving and methodical mindset and possessing a quick comprehension. I like to get deeply involved in complex challenges and aim to constantly learn new things — especially if it is related to web development and technical innovations in general. These skills and habits have been highly valuable during my five years of mathematical and technical education and in over four years of work as a (senior) consultant and web developer.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR CONSULTANT / WEB DEVELOPER, D-FINE, FRANKFURT

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT

D-fine is a specialized European consulting firm with scientifically minded employees, which provides innovative, customized and futureproof software solutions for complex challenges.

During my time with d-fine I am engaged in all steps of web development. Ranging from requirement gathering, solution design and coordination with business owners to implementation, testing and documentation — mostly in agile setups. Some of the larger projects I was involved with are:

EXTENSION OF A CRYPTO CURRENCY CUSTODIAN

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Feature implementation and setup of a CI/CD pipeline with a Kubernetes cluster for a highly regulated crypto currency custodian.

The pipeline included automated executions of test cases, vulnerability scans and the deployment - making manual tests and deployments superfluous. This increased the overall stability of the system and enabled faster and easier feature rollouts, while simultaneously reducing the risk of human errors.

The used tech stack includes: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, C#, ASP.NET Core, REST APIs, Docker, GitLab, CI/CD pipelines

EXTENSION OF A MICROSERVICE PLATFORM

JULY 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

Feature implementation for a microservice based platform for a new blockchain related market offering of a big German stock exchange in an agile team.

The project included support in the UI / UX design process and the creation of a fully responsive and cross-browser compatible landing page. A large redesign of the React based frontend to improve the user experience and the creation of an admin dashboard. The creation and extraction of reusable components into a component library to achieve a consistent look and feel over different services and to avoid code duplication. For the microservices based backend we designed

FLORIAN BÜHLER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

LANGUAGES

- German native
- English proficient
- Chinese beginner

CERTIFICATIONS

- Professional Scrum Master
- GitLab Certified Associate

UDEMY CERTIFICATES

- The Web Developer Bootcamp
- Modern HTML & CSS From The Beginning (Including Sass)
- The Git & GitHub Bootcamp
- Understanding TypeScript
- C# Intermediate: Classes, Interfaces and OOP

EDX

- Harvard CS50's Introduction to Computer Science
- Harvard CS50's Web
 Programming with Python and
 JavaScript

MASTER THESIS

Testing new Approaches for the Prediction of Global Stock Markets

BACHELOR THESIS

Efficient Approximation of the Value at Risk in a One-Factor Firm Value Model through Importance Sampling

and implemented several new features, available through a domain-driven RESTful application interface and integrated them into the user frontend and the admin dashboard.

All changes were automatically tested and continuously integrated into development environments on AWS and the on-premises production environment through GitLab CI/CD pipelines.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, Gatsby, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab, CI/CD pipelines

DEVELOPMENT OF A MOBILE COUPON PLATFORM

APRIL 2020 - JUNE 2020

Development of a responsive landing page and a mobile first single page application for a coupon platform from front to back in an agile team. Including the setup and configuration of a development, a pre-production and a production environment on AWS and GitLab CI/CD pipelines for automated testing and feature deployment.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, Gatsby, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab, CI/CD pipelines

DEVELOPMENT OF A MICROSERVICE PLATFORM (MVP)

FEBRUARY 2019 - APRIL 2020

Development of a microservice platform MVP for a big German stock exchange in an agile team. The MVP was a prototype for a crypto token emission platform, including user management, project management and the automatic creation, deployment and interaction with smart contracts on the blockchain.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab, CI/CD pipelines

• FEATURE DEVELOPMENT IN A FINANCIAL DATA WAREHOUSE

MARCH 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Analyzation and feature implementation of customer requirements in a financial data warehouse for a large German universal bank.

EDUCATION

ULM UNIVERSITY, DE - M. SC. IN MATHEMATICS AND ECONOMICS

OCTOBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2016, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (1.3)

Study of mathematics and economics with a focus on optimization, financial modeling and additional computer science courses.

MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, TR – ERASMUS SEMESTER

OCTOBER 2015 – JANUARY 2016, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (AA)

ULM UNIVERSITY, DE – B. SC. IN MATHEMATICS AND ECONOMICS

OCTOBER 2011 - JULY 2014, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (1.5)

Study of mathematics and economics with a focus on stochastic, financial mathematics and computer science.

During my bachelor studies I was doing an internship with ZEB Consulting, Münster. I was migrating several financial models from MATLAB to F# and created a custom Excel add-in to increase the usability and performance.